
[
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true of hypothyroidism?",
        "choices": [
            "A. T3 and T4 levels increase",
            "B. TSH levels decrease",
            "C. T3 and T4 levels decrease",
            "D. TSH levels increase"
        ],
        "answer": "A. T3 and T4 levels increase",
        "topic": "Endocrinology"
    },
    {
        "question": "A patient presents with bloating, pain, bowel habit changes, and passage of mucus. Which of the following is the MOST likely diagnosis?",
        "choices": [
            "A. Irritable Bowel Disease (IBD)",
            "B. Gastric Cancer",
            "C. Peptic Ulcer Disease",
            "D. Appendicitis"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Irritable Bowel Disease (IBD)",
        "topic": "Gastroenterology"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the primary source of energy during short term fasting (<5 days) in healthy adults?",
        "choices": [
            "A. Brown fat",
            "B. Glycogen",
            "C. Muscle protein and body fat",
            "D. Glucose"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Muscle protein and body fat",
        "topic": "Physiology"
    },
   {
        "question": "A patient with a spinal cord injury presents with motor function preserved below the neurological level, but less than half of key muscles below the neurological level have a muscle strength grade â‰¥ 3. What is the ASIA impairment scale classification?",
        "choices": [
            "A. ASIA A",
            "B. ASIA B",
            "C. ASIA C",
            "D. ASIA D"
        ],
        "answer": "C. ASIA C",
        "topic": "Neurology"
    },
    {
        "question": "A patient presents with a suspected lower urinary tract obstruction and has a palpable bladder. Which of the following conditions is MOST likely?",
        "choices": [
            "A. Gastritis",
            "B. Epigastric hernia",
            "C. Omphalocele",
            "D. Bladder outlet obstruction"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Bladder outlet obstruction",
        "topic": "Urology"
    },
   {
        "question": "A hypothyroid patient presents after brain surgery. Which of the following laboratory findings is expected?",
        "choices": [
            "A. Low TSH and low T3 and T4",
            "B. High TSH and low T3 and T4",
            "C. Low TSH and high T3 and T4",
            "D. High TSH and high T3 and T4"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Low TSH and low T3 and T4",
        "topic": "Endocrinology"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following spinal cord injury syndromes carries the WORST prognosis?",
        "choices": [
            "A. Anterior spinal cord syndrome",
            "B. Central cord syndrome",
            "C. Brown-Sequard syndrome",
            "D. Posterior cord syndrome"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Anterior spinal cord syndrome",
        "topic": "Neurology"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT considered a significant risk factor for chronic subdural hematoma?",
        "choices": [
            "A. Male gender",
            "B. Advanced age",
            "C. Anticoagulant use",
            "D. Alcoholism"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Male gender",
        "topic": "Neurology"
    },
   {
    "question": "A patient who cannot understand spoken language but can produce fluent speech (incoherent) most likely has a GCS verbal score of:",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1",
      "B. 2",
      "C. 3",
      "D. 4"
    ],
    "answer": "D. 4",
    "topic": "Neurology"
    },
 {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is FALSE regarding the American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) Physical Status Classification System?",
        "choices": [
            "A. ASA 5 describes a moribund patient who is not expected to survive without the operation.",
            "B. ASA 3 describes a patient with severe systemic disease.",
            "C. A patient with an EF of less than 30 would be classified as at least ASA 3.",
            "D. ASA classification reliably predicts operative risk."
        ],
        "answer": "D. ASA classification reliably predicts operative risk.",
        "topic": "Anesthesiology"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT an indication for emergency reversal of anticoagulation in a patient on warfarin?",
        "choices": [
            "A. Life-threatening bleeding.",
            "B. Head injury with intracranial hemorrhage.",
            "C. INR of 1.4",
            "D. Compartment syndrome."
        ],
        "answer": "C. INR of 1.4",
        "topic": "Surgery"
    },
    {
    "question":"What is the ammount of 3% hypertonic saline has in mEq/L of sodium?",
     "choices":[
       "A.154 meq/l",
       "B.513 meq/l",
       "C.300 meq/l",
       "D.450 meq/l"
     ],
     "answer":"B.513 meq/l",
     "topic":"Fluid and electrolyte"
    },

 {
        "question": "In which of the following locations is the administration of lidocaine with epinephrine CONTRAINDICATED?",
        "choices": [
            "A. Breast",
            "B. Nose",
            "C. Scalp",
            "D. Face"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Nose",
        "topic": "Anesthesiology"
    },
   {
        "question": "What is the approximate amount of carbohydrate stores, in the form of glycogen, in a normal adult body?",
        "choices": [
            "A. 100 to 200 g",
            "B. 300 to 400 g",
            "C. 500 to 600 g",
            "D. 700 to 800 g"
        ],
        "answer": "B. 300 to 400 g",
        "topic": "Physiology"
    },
  {
    "question": "A patient is on therapeutic heparin. What activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) value, relative to control, would suggest that reversal of anticoagulation might NOT be necessary before surgery?",
    "choices":[
      "A. Less than 1.3 times control",
      "B. 1.5 to 2.5 times control",
      "C. Greater than 2.5 times control",
      "D. Greater than 3.0 times control"
    ],
    "answer": "A. Less than 1.3 times control",
    "topic": "Hematology/Surgery"
  },
  {
      "question":"What is the recommended first line treatment option in the acute phase of a hypotensive and hypovolemic shock?",
      "choices":[
          "A. normal saline",
          "B. balanced crystalloid",
          "C. colloids",
          "D. blood products"
      ],
      "answer": "B. balanced crystalloid",
       "topic": "Fluid and electrolyte"
  },
    {
    "question": "When considering 'Bridging' anticoagulation in elective cases, Warfarin is typically discontinued how many days before the operation for those with INR 2-3",
    "choices":[
        "A. 1 day",
        "B. 2 days",
        "C. 4 days",
        "D. 7 days"

    ],
     "answer": "C. 4 days",
      "topic": "Surgery"
  },
    {
     "question":"which of the following is the recommended first line vasopressor in septic shock?",
     "choices":[
       "A. dopamine ",
       "B. dobutamine ",
       "C. epinephrine ",
       "D. norepinephrine "
     ],
      "answer": "D. norepinephrine ",
       "topic": "Fluid and electerolyte"
    },
    {
      "question": "What should be done as a First step management of shock?",
      "choices": [
       "A. Arresting the bleeding",
       "B. Antibiotics ",
       "C. ABC of life ",
       "D. Vasopressor "
      ],
       "answer":"C. ABC of life ",
       "topic": "surgery"
    },
    {
        "question": "What percentage of ICU patients experience nosocomial infections and are at risk of developing sepsis?",
        "choices":[
           "A. 10%",
           "B. 25%",
           "C. 50%",
           "D. 75%"
        ],
        "answer":"C. 50%",
        "topic": "Critical care"
    },
     {
        "question":"Which of the following is the most common form of shoch in ICU patients ?",
        "choices":[
         "A. cardiogenic shock",
         "B. septic shock",
         "C. Obstructive shock",
         "D. Hypovolemic shock"
        ],
        "answer": "B. septic shock",
        "topic": "Critical care "
     }
]